

☑ yahui.liu@unitn.it • ♀ yhlleo.github.io/

I am a PhD student in Computer Science at the Multimedia and Human Understanding Group (MHUG) of the University of Trento, Italy. I majored in Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System in Wuhan University, China, and received my M.E. degree in June 2018. Recently, my research focuses on Deep Learning and its applications in Computer Vision.

Education

University of Trento

Department of Information Engineering and Computer Science, Ph.D.
Supervisors: Prof. Nicu Sebe and Dr. Bruno Lepri

Wuhan University
Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System, Master of Engineering, GPA: 3.5/4.0
Supervisor: Prof. Jian Yao

Wuhan University
Remote Sensing Science and Technology, Bachelor of Engineering, GPA: 3.6/4.0

Italy

China
2018–2022

China
2011–2015

Research Experience

o Amazon, Berlin, Germany. Oct. 2020-Jan. 2021

Mentor: Dr. Weiwei Cheng. Machine/Deep Learning

o FBK & Multimedia and Human Understanding Group (MHUG), Trento, Italy. Dec. 2018-present

Mentors: Prof. Nicu Sebe and Dr. Bruno Lepri.

Deep learning, GANs, Cross-modal Representations, Image Domain Translation

o Tencent AI Lab, Shenzhen, China. Nov. 2017–Sep. 2018

Mentors: Dr. Wei Bi and Dr. Xiaojiang Liu.

Deep Learning, Neural Dialogue Generation, Natural Language Processing

o Computer Vision & Remote Sensing (CVRS) Lab, Wuhan, China. Mar. 2015–Oct. 2017

Mentor: Prof. Jian Yao.

Computer Vision, Remote Sensing, Deep Learning

Research Projects

Computer Vision....

Image Domain Translation

Python, Pytorch Mar. 2019–present

(1) Unsupervised multi-modal and multi-domain image-to-image translation, (2) Text-conditioned unsupervised image domain translation, (3) Generic method for improving translation quality.

Gesture-to-Gesture translation

Python, Pytorch Dec. 2018–Mar. 2019

proposed a novel method to achieve pretty hand gesture-to-gesture translation by using only a simple category independent conditional map.

Remote Sensing.....

Road Network Extraction

O Python, TensorFlow Jul. 2017–Nov. 2017

Designed a multi-task CNN for simultaneously extracting road surface, road edges and road centerlines from high resolution remotely sensed images (spatial resolution 0.21m).

Optimal Seamline Detection

C++, Python, Caffe

Jan. 2017-Jun. 2017

Proposed a method that combining the deep CNNs with Graph Cuts to get optimal seamline for stitching satellites' images.

Natural Language Processing

Neural Dialogue Generation

Python, TensorFlow, Pytorch

Nov. 2017–Sep. 2018

A research project of Tencent AI Lab, NLP Group in Shenzhen, China. I'm solving several issues of current state-of-the-art neural dialogue generation methods, such as generic/dull responses, short responses, and diversity of responses, etc.

Selected Publications

- 1 Yahui Liu, Marco De Nadai, Deng Cai, Huayang Li, Xavier Alameda-Pineda, Nicu Sebe, and Bruno Lepri. *Describe What to Change: A Text-guided Unsupervised Image-to-Image Translation Approach*, ACM MM (27.8%), Oct. 2020.
- 2 Raul Gomez*, Yahui Liu* (Co-first Author), Marco De Nadai, Dimosthenis Karatzas, Nicu Sebe, and Bruno Lepri. *Retrieval Guided Unsupervised Multi-domain Image-to-Image Translation*, ACM MM (27.8%), Oct. 2020.
- 3 Yahui Liu, Marco De Nadai, Gloria Zen, Nicu Sebe, and Bruno Lepri. Gesture-to-Gesture Translation in the Wild via Category-Independent Conditional Maps, ACM MM (26.5%, Oral), Oct. 2019.
- 4 Jing Han, Jian Yao, Jiao Zhao, Jingmin Tu, and **Yahui Liu**. *Multi-oriented and Scale Invariant License Plate Detection Based on Convolutional Neural Networks*, **Sensors** (IF: 3.03), Mar. 2019.
- 5 Yahui Liu, Jian Yao, Rengping Xie, and Li Li. DeepCrack: A Deep Hierarchical Feature Learning Architecture for Crack Segmentation, Neurocomputing (IF: 4.07), Jan. 2019.
- 6 Yahui Liu, Jian Yao, Xiaohu Lu, Menghan Xia, Xingbo Wang, and Yuan Liu. RoadNet: Learning to Comprehensively Analyze Road Networks in Complex Urban Scenes from High Resolution Remotely Sensed Images. IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing (TGRS, IF: 5.63), Sep. 2018.
- 7 Yahui Liu, Victoria Bi, Jun Gao, Xiaojiang Liu, Jian Yao, and Shuming Shi. *Towards Less Generic Responses in Neural Conversation Models: A Statistical Re-weighting Method*. EMNLP (23.2%, Oral), Aug. 2018.
- 8 Li Li, Jian Yao, **Yahui Liu**, Wei Yuan, Shuzhu Shi, and Shenggu Yuan. *Optimal Seamline Detection for Orthoimage Mosaicking by Combining Deep Convolutional Neural Network and Graph Cuts*, **Remote Sensing**, (IF: 4.12) Jul. 2017

Professional Activities

Reviewer:

- o IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics (2017, 2019, 2020)
- o IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters (2019, 2020)
- o IEEE Access (2019)
- o IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing (2020)
- o Complexity (2020)
- o ACM Multimedia (2020)

Member: Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)

Scholarships and Awards

- o 2018-2021, The Scholarship of University of Trento, Italy
- o 2017-2018, The Second Prize Scholarship, Wuhan University, China
- o 2016-2017, The First Prize Scholarship, Excellent Student, Wuhan University, China
- o 2015-2016, Excellent Bachelor Thesis of Hubei Province, China (top 4%)
- o 2014-2015, The Second Prize Scholarship, Excellent Student, Excellent Student Cadre, Wuhan Univeristy, China
- o 2013-2014, The Second Prize Scholarship, Excellent Student, Excellent Student Cadre, Wuhan University, China
- o 2012-2013, The Third Prize Scholarship, Excellent Student, Excellent Student Cadre, Wuhan University, China

Language Skills

- English, \geq B2
- o Mandarin, native speaker
- o Python (expert), C++ (fluent), Matlab (prior experience)